Storytelling is an ancient art form that has been used to hand down legends, tales and factual stories.
讲故事是一种古老的艺术形式，人们一直借助它来传承传说、民间故事和真实故事。
Perhaps the first thing that springs to mind when you think of storytelling is the fantasy land that took shape in your mind while Mom or Dad told you stories about princes, castles and monsters, with a unique voice for each character.
说起讲故事，你首先想到的也许是这样一片奇幻天地：妈妈或爸爸给你讲王子、城堡和怪物的故事，为每个角色配上独特的声音，而那片天地就在你的脑海中渐渐成形。
Storytelling does not just take place at bedtime or round a campfire, however.
不过，讲故事并不只发生在睡前或篝火旁。
It can take some other forms, either via the books we read or the films we watch.
它还可以采取其他一些形式，或是借助我们读的书，或是借助我们看的电影。
But they usually have some elements in common: rather than a list of dry facts, stories have plots and they introduce characters.
但它们通常有一些共同的要素：故事不是罗列一串枯燥的事实，而是有情节，还会引入人物。
We respond to stories, particularly when there is emotional detail.
我们会被故事打动，尤其是在故事中有情感细节的时候。
And contrary to what we may suppose, storytelling is not just a form of entertainment, but a form of learning as well.
而且，与我们可能以为的不同，讲故事不仅是一种娱乐形式，也是一种学习形式。
Long before reading and writing became widely spread and available, oral storytelling had already been a form through which the wisdom and knowledge of the people were passed down from elders to children.
早在阅读和写作广泛传播、普遍可及之前，口头讲故事就已经是一种传承方式，人们的智慧和知识借此由长辈传给孩子。
A good story engages our curiosity, emotions and imagination.
一个好故事能调动我们的好奇心、情感和想象力。
Storytelling helps with learning also because stories are easy to remember.
讲故事之所以有助于学习，还因为故事容易记住。
Research has found that learning obtained from a well-told story is remembered more accurately, and for far longer, than from facts and figures.
研究发现，与从事实和数据中学到的东西相比，从一个讲得好的故事中获得的知识会记得更准确，记住的时间也要长得多。
And above all, stories have a transformative power to allow us to see the world in a different way than we do if we just encounter it on our own.
而最重要的是，故事有一种改变人的力量，能让我们以不同于仅凭自己接触世界时的眼光来看待世界。
Stories are an entry point to understanding a different experience of the world.
故事是一个切入点，让我们得以理解对世界的另一种体验。
This aspect of storytelling—presenting a different perspective on the world—is important when it comes to connecting with each other.
讲故事的这一方面——呈现看待世界的不同视角——在人与人建立联系时非常重要。
It gives us an opportunity to learn from another person’s experience and it can shape, strengthen or challenge our opinions and values.
它让我们有机会从别人的经历中学习，还能塑造、强化或挑战我们的观点和价值观。
So, when someone tells us their own personal story, we catch a glimpse of a view of the world that may be slightly or significantly different from our own.
所以，有人给我们讲自己的亲身经历时，我们就能瞥见一种看待世界的视角，它与我们自己的视角可能略有不同，也可能大不相同。
When we see the world as they see it, or walk in their shoes, the experience can inspire empathy with them.
我们像对方那样看待世界，或者站在对方的立场上时，这种体验能激发我们对对方的共情。